Register of the Walther Schevenels Papers, 1901-1986
Hoover Institution Archives
- WORLD FEDERATION OF TRADE UNIONS (WFTU), 1945-1956
  - Reports
    - Submitted from within the WFTU to the Executive Bureau. Topics include: WFTU missions to Greece, Iran, Tunisia; representation of the WFTU in the United Nations; refugees
      - 1945 (Folder 9)
      - 1946 (Folder 10-11)
      - 1946 (Box 14., Folder 1)
      - 1948-1949 (Folder 2)
    - Submitted by the Executive Bureau to the United Nations on the subject of trade union rights, 1948 (Folder 3)
  - Speech by Louis Saillant, General Secretary of the WFTU, 1948 (Folder 4)
  - Subject file relating to activities of the WFTU
    - International Trade Union Conference on Teaching, Budapest, 1948. Article, resolutions and notes by Schevenels (Folder 5)
    - Iranian trade unions. Account of meeting between Secretary General of the WFTU and representatives of Iranian trade unions, 1945 (Folder 6)
    - Joint conferences of the International Trade Secretariats (ITS) and the WFTU
      - Circular letters (Folder 7)
      - Minutes. Includes notes by Schevenels
        - 1946 (Folder 8)
        - 1947 (Folder 9)
      - Press release (Folder 10)
      - Reports by Schevenels and others. Includes communications from trade union federations (Folder 11)
    - Membership. Evaluations (by Schevenels?) of political affiliations of WFTU leadership and staff, as well as record of visitors to headquarters in Paris (Folder 12)
    - United States Mission to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and European Regional Organizations (USRO). Reports on the WFTU
      - 1952-1953 (Folder 13)
      - 1954 (Folder 14)
      - 1955-1956 (Folder 15)
- EUROPEAN RECOVERY PROGRAM (ERP), TRADE UNION ADVISORY COMMITTEE, 1949-1951
  - Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 15., Folder 1)
- EUROPEAN REGIONAL ORGANIZATION (ERO) OF THE INTERNATIONAL CONFEDERATION OF FREE TRADE UNIONS (ICFTU), 1950-1964
  - Press release, 1949 (Box 15., Folder 2)
  - Clippings (Folder 3)
  - Constitution, 1957 (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1965 (Folder 5)
  - Manifestos and proclamations for May Day, 1951-1964 (Folder 6)
  - Memoranda
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Written by Schevenels (Folder 8)
  - Minutes
    - Economic Committee, 1957-1958 (Folder 9)
    - European Trade Union Committee on Youth, 1960 (Folder 10)
    - Executive Board and Executive Committee, 1954-1965 (Folder 11)
  - Notes by Schevenels on ERO activities (Folder 12)
  - Policy statements (Folder 13)
  - Press releases (Folder 14)
  - Proceedings
    - Conference Syndicale Europeenne du Logement, 1952 (Folder 15)
    - European Regional Conferences, 1954-1964 (Folder 16)
  - Publications (Folder 17)
  - Questionnaires. Includes cover letter (Folder 18)
  - Reports
    - Collective bargaining (Folder 19)
    - Young workers (Folder 20)
  - Resolutions (Folder 21)
  - Subject file relating to ERO activities
    - Congres Europeen du Travail, Paris, 1959 May 16-19. Resolution and speech (Folder 22)
    - European Trade Union Course, London, 1959 September 2-11. Lectures by J. A. Hargreaves and H. Ter Hiede (Folder 23)
    - Training Courses at ICFTU Headquarters, Brussels, 1956-1957
      - Correspondence (Folder 24)
      - Program outlines (Folder 25)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1940-1967
  - European integration. Includes material on Common Market and Council of Europe
    - Clippings (Box 16., Folder 1)
    - Notes by Schevenels (Folder 2)
    - Pamphlets and reports (Folder 3-4)
  - France
    - General. Clippings (Folder 5)
    - World War II and immediate aftermath
      - Bulletins, pamphlets and reports
        - General (Folder 6)
        - Confederation Generale du Travail (CGT) (Folder 7)
      - Clippings
        - 1940-1941 (Folder 8)
        - 1942-1943 (Folder 9)
        - 1944-1945 (Folder 10)
  - Germany
    - General. Book review and report (Folder 11)
    - World War II and immediate aftermath
      - Bulletins, pamphlets and reports (Folder 12)
      - Clippings
        - 1940-1942 (Box 17., Folder 1)
        - 1943-1945 (Folder 2)
  - Marshall Plan. Clippings (Folder 3)
  - May Day - History and commemorations
    - General. Notes by Schevenels, clippings and pamphlet (Folder 4)
    - Tougouchi, Marc, "Le Premier Mai," 1960. Mimeographed historical paper (Folder 5)
  - Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD)
    - Press release (Folder 6)
    - Reports on Yugoslavia (Folder 7)
  - Socialism
    - Clippings (Folder 8)
    - List of representatives of Labour and Socialist International (Folder 9)
    - Program for European Socialist Congress (Folder 10)
    - Publications (Folder 11)
  - Trade unions
    - Chronology of trade union movement, 1921-1928 (by Schevenels?) (Folder 12)
    - Clippings
      - General (Folder 13)
      - Belgium (Folder 14)
      - Great Britain (Folder 15)
    - Obituaries of trade union leaders
      - Ernest Bevin (Folder 16)
      - Hans Bockler (Folder 17)
      - Joseph Bondas (Folder 18)
      - Harold Butler (Folder 19)
      - Leon Chevalme (Folder 20)
      - Edo Fimmen (Folder 21)
      - Sidney Hillman (Folder 22)
      - Leon Jouhaux (Folder 23)
      - Jan Oudegeest (Folder 24)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 25)
    - Publications. Includes speeches and resolutions
      - American Federation of Labor (A.F.L.) (Folder 26)
      - Congress of Industrial Organizations (C.I.O.) (Folder 27)
      - Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund (DGB) (Folder 28)
      - La Federation Suisse des Typographes (Folder 29)
      - International Bookbinders' Union (Folder 30)
      - International Federation of Building- and Woodworkers (IBWW) (Box 18., Folder 1)
      - International Federation of Lithographers. Includes clipping (Folder 2)
      - Internationale du Personnel des Postes, Telegraphes et Telephones (IPTT) (Folder 3)
      - International Transport Workers' Federation (ITF) (Folder 4)
      - National Federation of Building Trades Operatives (Folder 5)
      - Nederlands Verbond van Vakverenigingen (N.V.V.) (Folder 6)
      - Norwegian Federation of Trade Unions (Folder 7)
      - Trades Union Congress (T.U.C.) (Folder 8)
    - Reports on labor in the United States (Folder 9)
  - United Nations Conference on International Organization, San Francisco, 1945. Minutes and reports (Folder 10-13)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO). Reports on workers' education and training (Box 19., Folder 1)
  - Youth employment and leisure. Includes information on youth hostels in Europe. Pamphlets (Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Clippings (Folder 3)
    - Notes on Versailles Peace Conference, 1919 (Folder 4)
    - Political cartoons (Folder 5)
    - Publications (Folder 6)
    - Report by Pierre Krier, 1941 May 20 (Folder 7)
    - Speech by Robert Lacoste, 1945 March 8 (Folder 8)
- CARD FILE, n.d.
  - Cards with addresses of correspondents. Unsorted (Folder 20.)